<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ketosoy on krishicks.com</title>
    <link>http://www.krishicks.com/tags/ketosoy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ketosoy on krishicks.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.krishicks.com/tags/ketosoy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>KetoSoy</title>
      <link>http://www.krishicks.com/post/ketosoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.krishicks.com/post/ketosoy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been consuming &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ketosoy.com&#34;&gt;KetoSoy&lt;/a&gt; for about a month now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-it:1f2ff74c1d28d8917c4851633b66f3c1&#34;&gt;What is it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KetoSoy is a chocolate flavored meal replacement shake engineered to make the ketogenic diet easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is similar in idea to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.soylent.com&#34;&gt;Soylent&lt;/a&gt;, though with a very different ingredient profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main difference between the two is carbohydrates. Soylent is high in carbohydrates. KetoSoy is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/09/02/health/low-carb-vs-low-fat-diet.html&#34;&gt;high in fat&lt;/a&gt; and low in carbohydrates to keep you in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ketosis&#34;&gt;ketosis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one serving:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;th&gt;Soylent 1.5&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;th&gt;KetoSoy 0.9&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Calories&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Calories from Fat&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;210&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;450&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Fat&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;24g&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;50g&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Carbohydrates&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;204g&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;24g&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Protein&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;21g&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;27g&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Protein source&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;rice&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;milk&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The complete nutrition profile of each is available at their respective sites.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why:1f2ff74c1d28d8917c4851633b66f3c1&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw KetoSoy mentioned on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/soylent/comments/2o02kx/as_promised_ketosoy_the_ketogenic_soylent_is_now/&#34;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; while checking up on the state of Soylent. The ingredient profile of Soylent never appealed to me, but KetoSoy&amp;rsquo;s looked right up my alley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been aiming for a high-fat, low-carb, Paleo-ish diet for about a year now. I don&amp;rsquo;t cook at home; I eat out exclusively (or in, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://munchery.com&#34;&gt;Munchery&lt;/a&gt;). I wanted an alternative for the times that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to go out, when Munchery&amp;rsquo;s menu didn&amp;rsquo;t look enticing, or when I wanted to limit my caloric intake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also much cheaper than going out: with the monthly subscription a 15-day supply comes out to $10 &lt;strong&gt;per day&lt;/strong&gt; (without the subscription, $12.50). Adding the extra protein powder and chia seeds does increase this, but only slightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how:1f2ff74c1d28d8917c4851633b66f3c1&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prepare a day&amp;rsquo;s worth (3 servings) of KetoSoy, I use these steps with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.com/B00LBFUKIA&#34;&gt;Vitamix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prep:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;210g of KetoSoy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;84g of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.com/B0015AQL1Q&#34;&gt;flavorless protein powder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.com/B00H889MGK&#34;&gt;chia seeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put the KetoSoy, protein powder, and chia seeds in a large container, like a &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.com/B00MVMCUK8&#34;&gt;Blender Bottle&lt;/a&gt; or a re-used, clean and empty KetoSoy oil bottle with the top cut off&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add 8 cups of water to the Vitamix container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add 10 tablespoons of the oil included with KetoSoy to the Vitamix container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blend the water and oil to emulsify them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the Vitamix on its lowest setting, slowly add the protein powder until it&amp;rsquo;s blended&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slowly add the chia seeds, increasing the speed of the Vitamix as necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slowly add the KetoSoy, increasing the speed of the Vitamix as necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process, while not perfect, has yielded the most repeatable results for me so far. If I run into any issues blending I&amp;rsquo;ll pour out the contents of the Vitamix into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.com/B00DCYNP2G&#34;&gt;2-liter airtight pitcher&lt;/a&gt; I plan to store the finished mixture in, then slowly pour it back into the Vitamix, starting at a low speed and increasing it until everything is properly blended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed I do not add the optional liquid sweetener. I find the flavor profile to be delicious without it, and the sweetener only ruins it. I only tried the liquid Stevia, for what it&amp;rsquo;s worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The texture and taste are both wonderful, especially with the added protein powder and chia seeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;effects:1f2ff74c1d28d8917c4851633b66f3c1&#34;&gt;Effects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did lose some weight, which might alarm people that know me. I went from 82kg to 77kg within the first week of KetoSoy (this leads me to believe ketosis was achieved, but I cannot confirm as I did not test it empirically). My weight does rapidly go back up to 80kg if I eat what I would normally eat all the time, which I now only eat sparingly (the pork chop at &lt;a href=&#34;http://nopasf.com&#34;&gt;NOPA&lt;/a&gt;, the fried chicken at &lt;a href=&#34;http://magnoliapub.com/&#34;&gt;Magnolia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any gastrointestinal issues with KetoSoy, something that Soylent users have &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/soylent/comments/32t042/lpt_drink_slowly_to_avoid_bloatinggas/&#34;&gt;repeatedly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/soylent/comments/2qaw3o/has_anyone_else_gotten_way_less_gas_with_soylent/&#34;&gt;talked&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/soylent/comments/2cwxwq/day_7_official_soylent_still_having_gas/&#34;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/soylent/comments/2uuqac/a_little_over_a_week_in_on_ketosoy/&#34;&gt;mental fog&lt;/a&gt;, though I do add ~500 calories (the added protein powder and chia seeds).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also don&amp;rsquo;t believe I actually ever get into ketosis (despite the weight loss), though I have yet to actually test this with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.com/B001DCV9S6&#34;&gt;test strips&lt;/a&gt;. My breath never seems to become &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webmd.com/oral-health/features/low-carb-diets-can-cause-bad-breath&#34;&gt;ketosis-breath&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-i-recommend-it:1f2ff74c1d28d8917c4851633b66f3c1&#34;&gt;Do I recommend it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. The price is right, and the texture and taste is lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I began this process I had full bloodwork done. After doing KetoSoy for a while longer I will get bloodwork done again to see if there are any changes, good or bad, and update this post with the results. The bloodwork I got back before showed me in fantastic health.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>